Now, we can do a lot more with files then just look at them,
除了查看、移动和删除文件外
move them, and delete them.
我们还可以对文件做更多事
For instance, let's take that dictionary
例如 我们拿取你前面下载的那个
file you downloaded earlier and use it
目录文件 然后用它来
to see if a word is in the dictionary.
检查看某个单词是否在此目录中
There's a Shell command called grep
有一个叫做 grep 的 Shell 命令
that knows how to search a text file for lines
它知道如何在文本文件中搜索
with particular contents.
具有特定内容的行
If you give it a word, such as shell,
如果你给它一个单词 如 shell
and a file name like dictionary.txt,
和一个文件名 如 dictionary.txt
it will read the file and output all the lines
它会读取文件并输出
that contain that word.
包含该词的所有行
But what if, as in this case, there are more lines than we
但是 如果像这种情况 输出的行太多
can see at once.
我们没法一次看完 该怎么办呢
Well, one thing we can do is to ask
一种办法是我们可以
the Shell to send the output of grep into the less command.
要求 Shell 将 grep 的输出发送给 less 命令
You can do this with the pipe or the vertical bar character.
你可以使用竖线或管道符号 | 这么做
What's going on here?
那么现在是什么情况呢？
Well, the grep program reads the input file
grep 程序读取输入文件
and prints out any lines that match the pattern.
并打印出与该模式匹配的任何行
But the Shell has arranged things
但 Shell 做了安排
so that the output doesn't go directly to the terminal.
使输入不会直接到达终端
Instead it gets sent into the less program,
而是将输入发送给 less 程序
which displays those lines of the terminal one page
它会一次一页将这些行显示给
at a time.
终端
To read this command out loud, you'd
要念出这个命令 你可以
say grep for shell in dictionary.txt and pipe
说对 dictionary.txt 文件执行 grep shell 命令 然后传送
it to less.
给 less 程序
Now, grep can also operate on input from another program.
你也可以对来自另一个程序的输入执行 grep 命令
For instance, you can pull a file from the web using cURL
例如你可以使用 cURL 从网络中提取文件
and immediately grep it for a particular pattern
并立即对它使用 grep 命令来获取符合特定模式的内容
without having to save it to a file first.
而无需先将它保存到一个文件
The output from this cURL command
此 cURL 命令的输出
gets fed into this grep command as its input,
会作为输入馈送给这个 grep 命令
instead of grep reading from a file.
而非从文件中进行 grep 读取
As you can see, sometimes some of the output from cURL,
可以看到 有时 cURL 的一些输出
like this progress meter, gets mixed in with some
像这个进度表 会和 grep 的一些输出
of the output from grep--
混合在一起
so that can be a little confusing.
会让人有点困惑
They're actually not getting mixed to the Shell,
实际上它们并没有在 Shell 中混合
but they're getting mixed on our terminal.
而是在终端混合了
If we sent this to a file, it would be fine.
如果我们将它发送到一个文件 并不会有问题
It wouldn't get mixed in.
不会出现混合的现象
Now if you just wanted to know how many matches there are,
如果你只想知道有多少匹配
like how many words there are that contain the string fish,
比如有多少单词包含字符串 fish
there are a couple of different ways you can do that.
这样做的方法有好几个
One of them is to pipe the output of grep
一种方法是将 grep 的输出
into the word count program, or wc,
输送给 wc（字数）程序
and ask it to count lines with its dash little l option.
并加上 -l 选项让它计算行数
There we got the number 105.
这里我们得到的数字是 105
Another way is to give grep the option dash little c for count.
另一个方法是给 grep 加上 -c 用于计数
And there's the same 105.
同样得到 105